<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="belaban@yahoo.com">Bela Ban</author>
    <title>Various demos</title>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Draw">
<p>
Shows 2 instances of Draw and a graceful leave, plus a
crash-leave. 
The flash demo can be found <a href="../movies/DrawDemo.swf">here</a>.
<br/>
The Java Webstart demo can be found 
<a href="jnlp/draw.jnlp">here</a> (start multiple instances).
</p>
<p>
Note that you need a resolution of at least 1200x1024 to view the
flash presentations !
</p>
</section>



<section name="Draw with state">
<p>
Shows 2 instances of Draw which share a common state. The state is the
canvas onto which we draw.<br/>
The flash demo can be found <a href="../movies/DrawDemoWithState.swf">here</a>.
</p>
</section>



<section name="Whiteboard">
<p>
Shows 2 instances of Whiteboard. Whiteboard is a simple presence
application, showing each cluster node with a box with the user's name
and information about the operating system and JGroups address.<br/>
There's also a simple chatting functionality, where messages can be
sent to individual nodes, or to all nodes in the cluster.
<br/>
The flash demo can be found <a href="../movies/WhiteboardDemo.swf">here</a>.
</p>
</section>




<section name="ReplicatedHashMap">
<p>
Here we show 2 clustered stock servers, which replicate data between
themselves. Any update (addition, modification or removal) is
replicated between the servers.<br/>
We also show how a new server acquires the stocks from an existing
member (state transfer) and how a server can be restarted without the
cluster losing its shared state.
<br/>
The flash demo can be found <a href="../movies/ReplicatedHashMap.swf">here</a>.
</p>
</section>





<section name="ProtocolStack">
<p>
Here we show how to run the Draw demo with different stacks. The first
example is UDP, then we look at the different protocols and then use
TCP.
<br/>
The flash demo can be found <a href="../movies/ProtocolStack.swf">here</a>.
</p>
</section>



<section name="ReplCache">
<p>
This demo shows 4 instances of ReplCache forming a cluster (cloud
storage). The demo can be downloaded from 
<a href="http://downloads.sourceforge.net/javagroups/replcachedemo.jar">http://downloads.sourceforge.net/javagroups/replcachedemo.jar</a>
<br/>
The flash demo can be found 
<a href="../movies/ReplCache.swf">here</a>.
<br/>
The Java Webstart demo can be found 
<a href="jnlp/replcache.jnlp">here</a> (start multiple instances).

</p>
</section>



</body>
</document>

