<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="belaban@yahoo.com">Bela Ban</author>
    <title>HSQLDB/R</title>
  </properties>

<body>



<section name="Overview">
<p>
HSQLDB/R is an experimental alpha version of database replication for
the <a href="http://hsqldb.sf.net">HSQLDB open source Java
database</a>. It uses a modified copy of HSQLDB 1.7.1-alpha and
provides the following:
<ul>
<li>Replication between any number of databases. No master-slave
concept, pure peer-to-peer</li>
<li>Changes to one database will be replicated to all others</li>
<li>New nodes acquire full database from existing nodes or - if no
node exists yet - initializes itself from file</li>
</ul>
This implementation will be integrated into one of the next versions
of HSQLDB. The current implementation can be used to replicate changes
to one database to all other replicas. This is mainly used to failover
to a hot-standby dabatase server in case the primary database server
crashes.
<br/>It is possible <em>but not
recommended</em> to modify both replicas at the same time (see
documentation below for details). We will provide this capability in
the (near) future. Other items on the todo list are:
<ul>
<li>Transfer of large state: instead of transferring the entire
contents of the database (including e.g. all table definitions, users,
and table contents), we will dump the existing contents into a file,
load the new replica from file (offline) and then only request the
update log from the existing member</li>
<li>Binary format for replication. Currently we ship the SQL
statements as strings, in the future we will use an efficient internal
format. This also avoids having to parse the SQL statements again
before applying them to the database</li>
<li>Distributed locking: this will allow 2 applications to modify
<em>any</em> of the replicas (even the same data), and JGroups will
prevent conflicts.</li>
</ul>
</p>
</section>

<section name="Documentation">
<p>
The documentation is available in <a href="hsqldbr/design.doc">MS Word</a> 
and <a href="hsqldbr/design.pdf">PDF</a> format and as 
<a href="hsqldbr/design.htm">HTML</a>.
</p>
</section>


<section name="Download">
<p>
The hsqldbr.zip file can be downloaded from the 
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=6081">
regular SourceForge download page for JGroups</a>. It contains all
the necessary JARs and configuration files to run HSQLDB/R, including
a minimal JGroups and a modified HSQLDB (based on HSQLDB-1.7.1). We
will shortly integrate our changes into the HSQLDB code base, so the
modified version of HSQLDB will not be needed any longer.
</p> 
</section>

</body>
</document>

