<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="belaban@yahoo.com">Bela Ban</author>
        <title>The JGroups Project</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="">
            <!--img src="/images/jgroups_logo_450px.png" alt="JGroups logo"/-->
            <p>
                JGroups is a toolkit for reliable messaging. It can be used to create clusters whose
                nodes can send messages to each other. The main features include
                <ul>
                    <li>Cluster creation and deletion. Cluster nodes can be spread across LANs or WANs</li>
                    <li>Joining and leaving of clusters</li>
                    <li>Membership detection and notification about joined/left/crashed cluster nodes</li>
                    <li>Detection and removal of crashed nodes</li>
                    <li>Sending and receiving of node-to-cluster messages (point-to-multipoint)</li>
                    <li>Sending and receiving of node-to-node messages (point-to-point)</li>
                </ul>

            </p>
        </section>


<section name="Flexible Protocol Stack">
    <p>
        The most powerful feature of JGroups is its flexible protocol stack, which allows developers to adapt it to
        exactly match their application requirements and network characteristics.<br/>
        The benefit of this is that you only pay for what you use. By mixing and matching protocols, various
        differing application requirements can be satisfied.<br/>
        JGroups comes with a large number of protocols (but anyone can write their own), for example

        <ul>
            <li>Transport protocols: UDP (IP Multicast) or TCP</li>
            <li>Fragmentation of large messages</li>
            <li>Reliable unicast and multicast message transmission. Lost messages
                are retransmitted</li>
            <li>Failure detection: crashed nodes are excluded from the membership</li>
            <li>Flow control to prevent slow receivers to get overrun by fast senders</li>
            <li>Ordering protocols: FIFO, Total Order</li>
            <li>Membership</li>
            <li>Encryption</li>
            <li>Compression</li>
        </ul>

    </p>
</section>


<section name="What Does JGroups Buy Me ?">
    <p>
        JGroups allows developers to create reliable messaging (one-to-one or one-to-many)
        applications where <i>reliability</i> is a deployment issue, and does
        not have to be implemented by the application developer. This saves
        application developers significant amounts of time, and allows for the
        application to be deployed in different environments, without having
        to change code.
    </p>
</section>


<section name="About this Website">
    <p>

        This website was generated from XML using
        <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/velocity/index.html">Velocity</a> and
        the excellent <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/site/jakarta-site2.html">Jakarta-site2</a> projects.

    </p>
</section>


</body>
</document>

