<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="belaban@yahoo.com">Bela Ban</author>
    <title>Members</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Team Members">
<p>
<br/>These are the team members :<br/>


<table border="2" width="95%" height="15%" cellpadding="5">

<tr align="left">
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Bela Ban</b>
<a href="resume.html"><img src="images/bela.jpg"/></a><br/>
Born in Switzerland in 1965, I did my Masters and PhD (in network
management) at the University of Zurich.  After a stint at IBM
Research and various smaller companies, I moved to Ithaca, NY, for a
2-year post-doc at Cornell. Instead of returning to Switzerland, I
moved on to God's Own Country (California) where I currently work as a
principal software engineer at Fujitsu Network Communications (EMS/NMS
systems). My interests include network protocols, group communication,
Linux, Java, trail running, triathlon and beerathlon. If not hacking
on JGroups I can be found spending time with my family.<br/>
Bela is the creator of JGroups (during his post-doc at
Cornell). His main focus in JGroups is currently
<ul>
<li>Performance improvements (both speed and memory wise</li>
<li>Bug fixing and stability improvements</li>
<li>Figuring out how to make money with open source</li>
</ul>
</td>

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Vladimir Blagojevic</b>
<img src="images/vladimir.jpg"/><br/>
Originally from Yugoslavia, stuck in Canada since 1995.  Recently
graduated with Honours degree in Computer Science from York University
in Toronto. Got involved with JGroups while still an
undergrad. Currently works as a Java developer on server side platform
for wireless POS devices.<br/>
Vladimir created the CAUSAL and TOTAL_TOKEN protocols and also worked
on a number of performance related issues. 
</td>
</tr>




<tr align="left">
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Filip Hanik</b>
<img src="images/filip.png"/><br/>
I was born in Sweden in 1975 where I studied Computer Science and
Engineering at Chalmers University of Technology. After a few years in the
Swedish corporate environment I decided it was time to broaden my
experience. I moved to San Francisco in 1997 where I have been working with
distributed server systems using Java, Corba and J2EE technologies.
Today my professional focus is still on distributed server systems and with
a special attachment to clustering and fail over.
In my spare time I'm almost always occupied with yoga, meditation, salsa
dancing and motorcycle riding.<br/>
Filip integrated the ANT build system into JGroups, and also added
XML-based configuration of protocol stack specs. He recently used
JGroups to implement <a
href="http://www.theserverside.com/resources/article.jsp?l=Tomcat">session
clustering in Tomcat</a> and is currently integrating JGroups into
Tomcat.
</td>

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Sacha Labourey</b>
<img src="images/sacha.jpg"/><br/>
Sacha is the founder of Cogito Informatique, a Swiss company mainly
working in the application servers and middlewares fields.  He was born
in 1975 in Neuchatel (Switzerland), and owns a Master in computer
science from the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology.<br/>
Sacha is the main implementor of the load-balancing/failover for <a
href="http://www.jboss.org">JBoss</a> using JGroups.
</td>

</tr>


<tr align="left">

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>John Giorgiadis</b>
<img src="images/john.jpg"/><br/>
I was born in 1975. I did my first degree at the Electronic
Eng. Dept. of the Polytechnic Institute of Crete and a PhD at the
Dept. of Computing at Imperial College on adaptive component
architectures. I like group comm. (obviously), and the investigation
of related performance and scalability issues.<br/>

John reimplemented the NakReceiverWindow and wrote the implementation
of the TOTAL protocol (sequencer-based). The NakReceiverWindow is a
central piece of reliable multipoint message transmission and has
worked like a charm (and very performant !) ever since it was
rewritten.<br/>
John promised to send a better picture soon :-)
</td>

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Roman Rokytskyy</b>
<img src="images/roman.jpg"/><br/>
Born in Ukraine in 1976, I got my diploma with honors of Specialist in
Radio-Physics and Electronics (equivalent to Masters of Sciences) from Lviv
National University in 1998. The same year I entered PhD program at Glushkov
Institute of Cybernetics, Kiev, Ukraine, but in 2000 I postponed my research
and moved to Berlin (Germany). Fields of my interest include distributed
systems, intelligent software agents, databases, photography, voleyball and
skiing.

</td>

</tr>




<tr align="left">


<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Gianluca Collet</b>
<br/>
Gianluca implemented a first version of partition merging protocol
(MERGE and GMS).
</td>


<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Jim Menard</b>
<br/>
Jim implemented the excellent Trace subsystem (org.jgroups.log).
</td>


</tr>


<tr align="left">

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Mandar Shinde</b>
<img src="images/mandar.jpg" width="137" height="149"/>
<br/>
I was born (1976) and brought up in Bombay, India.
Graduated with Bachelors, Comp Eng from Bombay
University and Masters, Comp. Science from University
of Delaware. Joined Fujitsu Network Communications in
1999 with the Network Management Systems team and have been
there since.
Like to work in large-scale deployed distributed
systems, tuning peer-peer communication, ad-hoc
messaging and transactional related issues.
Hobbies include playing cricket, running and gym. Love
to watch any competitive sport.<br/>
Mandar implemented the persistence manager for DistributedHashtable,
and the ENCRYPT protocol.
</td>


<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Ovidiu Feodorov</b>
<img src="images/ovidiu.jpg"/>
<br/>
Born in Romania in 1972, I got my MSc in Computer Sciences at
University Politehnica of Bucharest. Since 1999 I live and work in Bay
Area, California, trying to mix together geophysics and Java
programming.<br/> 
My current areas of interest are client-server systems, J2EE,
application level network collaboration (and hence JGroups, which
came as a very useful tool at the right moment) and in general
creating Java applications that work and the users are happy
about. Currently I am concentrating on the WAN aspects of
JGroups.<br/>
Otherwise skiing, hiking, tennis, watching movies and
meeting with friends succeed keeping me 100% busy.
</td>


</tr>



<tr align="left">

<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>Chris Mills</b>
<img src="images/chris.jpg" width="137" height="149"/>
<br/>

Born in England in 1979, Chris started his programming career at a
small consultancy in deepest Gloucestershire using one of the first
Java application servers.  He moved on to work for Silverstream
Software where he held a Senior Consultant position.  Novell acquired
Silverstream in 2002 and Chris worked for both Novell UK and Novell
New Zealand.  After almost 2 years as the Solution Architect at Novell
NZ, Chris moved back to the UK to take a position at JBoss.
 
Chris is currently running the Systems Engineering team in EMEA and
likes to keep his hand in by helping out on some of the projects.  In
his spare time he enjoys playing rugby, drinking beer, reading,
drinking beer and oh drinking beer!
</td>



</tr>


</table>


<br/>
For a list of current committers click
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/memberlist.php?group_id=6081">here</a>.

</p>
  </section>



</body>
</document>

