<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="belaban@yahoo.com">Bela Ban</author>
    <title>Papers</title>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Papers and articles on JGroups (a bit dated)">
<p>

<ul>

<li><a href="papers/proposal.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: Adding Group Communication to Java in a Non-Intrusive Way 
Using the Ensemble Toolkit</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/Patterns.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: JavaGroups - Group Communication Patterns in Java</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/MethodResolution.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: Static vs. Dynamic Method Resolution in Java: 
The Case For Argument-Based Method Selection</a>
    (Code: <a href="papers/MethodCall.java">MethodCall.java</a>, 
           <a href="papers/MethodCallTest.java">MethodCallTest.java</a>   )
</li>

<li>(Rough Draft) <a href="papers/Funclets.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: Building Blocks for Client and Server Functionality in Group Protocols: The
Funclets Pattern</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/Coots.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: Design and Implementation of a Reliable Group Communication Toolkit for Java
</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/state.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: State Transfer in the JavaGroups Toolkit (draft)
</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/rmc.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: Implementing Group Protocols Using Dynamic Remote Method Invocations (draft)
</a>
</li>

<li><a href="papers/Middleware.ps.gz">
Bela Ban: A Simple Deadlock Resolution Scheme for Synchronous Reliable Group RPC (draft)
</a>
</li>

<li><a href="http://www.theserverside.com/resources/article.jsp?l=Tomcat">
Filip Hanik: In Memory Session Replication in Tomcat 4
</a>. Discussion of session replication in Tomcat 4. Step-by-step
instructions how to set up session replication in two Tomcat instances.
</li>

<li><a href="papers/totaltoken.ps.gz">
Vladimir Blagojevic: Implementing Totem's total ordering protocol in
JavaGroups reliable group communication toolkit.
</a> Detailed discussion of JGroups' TOTAL_TOKEN protocol as
implemented by Vladimir. Discussion of performance measurements.
</li>

<li>
<a href="papers/FlowControl.html">
Ananda Bollu: The JavaGroups FLOW_CONTROL Protocol
</a>
Overview and configuration of the FLOW_CONTROL protocol
</li>

<li>
<a href="http://www-106.ibm.com/developerworks/java/library/j-cluster1/">
High-impact Web tier clustering, Part 1: Scaling Web services and
applications with JavaGroups (IBM developWorks)
</a>
Detailed discussion of JGroups' concepts using session replication
as an example.
</li>



</ul>


</p>
</section>



<section name="Reliable Group Communication">
<p>

<li><a href="http://www.manning.com/Birman/">
Ken Birman: Building Secure and Reliable Network Applications.
</a> Excellent book on group communication. In-depth description of
various protocols (atomic bcast, causal, total order, probabilistic
broadcast). Very technical content.
</li>

</p>
</section>


<section name="Open Source">
<p>

<ul>

<li><a href="papers/OpenSource.pdf">
Open Source - A New Software Development Paradigm
</a>
</li>

</ul>


</p>
</section>


</body>
</document>

